A Guide to the Additional Henry Hughes Presler Papers
University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library, #11208-a
Additional Henry Hughes Presler Papers ca. 1909-1965
University of Virginia. Library. Special Collections Dept. Alderman Library University of Virginia Charlottesville, Virginia 22903 USA
11208-a
ca. 600 items
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
This collection bears no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
These papers were given to the University of Virginia Library by Marion C.A. Presler, Fargo, North Dakota, on December 6, 1997.
Scope and Content
This addition to the papers of Henry H. Presler consists of fifty-three files of maps and map indexes, ca. 600 items (3 Hollinger boxes) ca. 1909-1965, pertaining to Jabalpur, India, (spelled Jubbulpore on most maps) and the work of Dr. Presler who studied the religious institutions of the region following India's independence. For further information about this study please see the guide for #11208 and Presler's own guides to this material located in Box 1 of #11208.
Organization
These files were kept in the original order and arrangement created by Dr. Henry H. Presler.
LISTING OF MAPS
- Key to Jubbulpore City map, 1949 Aug-1950 (Box Box 1)
- "Plan of Jubbulpore Town and Cantonment Area including G.C.F. Estate, Arsenal, and Khamaria", 1947 Jun 21 (Box Box 1)
- Original Blueprint of Index Sketch map of Jubbulpore - Town, 1949 Sep 4 (Box Box 1)
- "Index sketch map of Jubbulpore - Town", 1948 Dec 31 (Box Box 1)
- St. Paul's C.M.S. Church, [Ghamapur] by T.N. Karim, 1954 Sep 3 (Box Box 1)
- Wards 1 & 2, ca. 1959-1965; (2 folders) (Box Box 1)
- Wards 3-10, ca. 1951-1965; (2 folders) (Box Box 1)
- Wards 11-20, ca. 1949-1955; (2 folders) (Box Box 1)
- Wards 21-30, ca. 1950-1961; (2 folders) (Box Box 2)
- South Civil Station, Ward 27, with sacred locations, 1949, 1959 (Box Box 2)
- "The Strength of the Non-Roman Christian Churches in the Districts of India & Pakistan" (Box Box 2)
- Bel Bagh Ward 20 Sacred Locations Visited, 1959 (Box Box 2)
- Plan of the City & Cantonment of Jubbulpore, with index of important roads & buildings (copies), 1909 (Box Box 2)
- "North Civil Station Ward 26" All Sacred Locations Visited, 1959 (Box Box 2)
- Jubbulpore Brigade Military Directory, 1939; (Fragile & Damaged) (Box Box 2)
- North of Kundum Road; South of Kundum Road; Khanchanpura, ca. 1950-1955 (Box Box 2)
- Ward 5 and Wright Town Ward 15, 1949-1953 (Box Box 2)
- Ward 1 - Maps, ca. 1949-1952 (Box Box 2)
- Ward 2 - Maps, 1949-1957 (Box Box 2)
- Ward 3 - Maps, 1949-1952 (Box Box 2)
- Ward 4 - Map, 1955 (Box Box 2)
- Ward 5 - Maps, 1949-1952 (Box Box 2)
- Ward 6 - Maps, 1949-1952 (Box Box 2)
- Ward 7 - Maps, 1949-1952 (Box Box 2)
- Ward 8 - North Milonigang, 1949-1952 (Box Box 2)
- Ward 9 - Gohalpur, 1952-1955 (Box Box 2)
- Ward 10 Moti Nala, 1949-1952 (Box Box 2)
- Deserted Villages, ca. 1950-1962 (Box Box 3)
- Ward 11 - Kotwali, 1949-1952 (Box Box 3)
- Ward 12 - Hanuman Tal, 1949-1952 (Box Box 3)
- Ward 14 - Lordganj, 1949-1952 (Box Box 3)
- Ward 15 (Wright Town), 1949-1955 (Box Box 3)
- Ward 16 - Mahartal, 1949-1959 (Box Box 3)
- Ward 17 - Omti, 1949-1952 (Box Box 3)
- Ward 18 - Bharipur, 1949-1952 (Box Box 3)
- Ward 19 - Galgala, 1949-1952 (Box Box 3)
- Ward 20 - Bel Bagh, 1949-1952, 1959 (Box Box 3)
- Ward 21 - Bhan Talaiya, ca. 1949-1952 (Box Box 3)
- Ward 22 - West Kariapather, 1949-1960 (Box Box 3)
- Ward 23 - East Kariapather, 1949-1952 (Box Box 3)
- Ward 24 - West Ghamhapur, 1949-1952 (Box Box 3)
- Ward 25 - East Ghamhapur, 1949-1952 (Box Box 3)
- Ward 26 - North Civil Station, 1949-1952 (Box Box 3)
- Ward 27 - South Civil Station, 1949-1952 (Box Box 3)
- Ward 28 - Napier Town, 1949-1952 (Box Box 3)
- Ward 29 - Gorakhpur, 1949-1952 (Box Box 3)
- Ward 30 - Madan Mahal, 1949-1952 (Box Box 3)
- Maps for Enlargement, n.d. (Box Box 3)
- Various maps of Jubbulpore Town, 1950 (Box Box 3)
- Various Ward Maps, ca. 1949-1954; (8x11) (Box Box 3)
- Cantonment Area - Combined & Miscellaneous Wards, 1951-1952 (Box Box 3)
- Government Farms - Khamaria, 1959 (Box Box 3)
- Plan of Jubbulpore Town and Cantonment Area, with religious sites located, ca. 1909-1951 (Box Box 3)